So here's an interesting observation;
有个事情很有意思：
in order to minimize the mean squared error,
为了最小化均方误差
we do not actually need to use gradient descent or the tricks.
我们实际上不需要梯度下降法或技巧
We can actually do this in a closed mathematical form. Let me show you.
我们可以在封闭的数学形式中完成 让我来展示一下
Here's our data x_1,
这是我们的数据 (X1,Y1)
y_1 all the way to x_m,
直到 (Xm,Ym)
y_m; and in this case, m is five.
在这个例子中 m 为 5
And the areas of the squares represent our squared error.
这些正方形区域代表了我们的平方误差
So our input is x_1 up to x_m and our labels are y_1 up to y_m,
所以我们输入点 X1 直到 Xm 标签为 Y1 直到 Ym
and our predictions are of the form y_i hat equals w_1 x_i plus w_2,
我们预测的形式是 Yi-hat = W1 Xi + W2
where w_1 is a slope of the line and w_2 is the y-intercept.
W1 是直线的斜率 W2 是 y 轴截距
And the mean squared error is given by this formula over here.
通过这个公式得到均方误差是这样的
Notice that I've written the error as a function of w_1 and w_2,
注意这里我写的误差为函数 W1 和 W2
since given any w_1 and w_2 we can calculate
因为给定了任何 W1 和 W2
the predictions and the error based on these values of w_1 and w_2.
我们可以根据 W1 和 W2 计算预测和误差
Now, as we know from calculus,
如果你学过微积分 你就会知道
in order to minimize this error,
为了最小化误差
we need to take the derivatives with respect to
我们需要根据两个输入变量 W1 和 W2 求导
the two input variables w_1 and w_2 and set them both equal to zero.
将两个都设为 0
We calculate the derivatives and you can see
我们计算导数 你可以
the full calculation in the instructor notes and we get these two formulas.
在教学笔记里看到整个运算 并且我们得到这两个公式
Now, we just need to solve for w_1 and w_2 for these two equations to be zero.
现在我们只需要解决 W1 和 W2 为 0 的两个方程
So what do we have now?
那么我们现在得到什么呢？
We have a system of two equations and two unknowns,
我们得到二元方程组 含有两个未知数
we can easily solve this using linear algebra.
我们可以使用线性代数很容易地解决这个问题
So now the question is,
所以另一个问题是
why don't we do this all the time?
为什么干脆不这样就好了？
Why do we have to go through many gradient descent steps
为什么我们需要通过梯度下降法
instead of just solving a system of equations and unknowns?
而不是只对含有未知数的方程组求解呢？
Well, think about this.
这样来考虑一下
If you didn't have only two dimensions in the input but you had n,
如果你输入的不是只有两个维度 而是有 n 个
then you would have n equations with n unknowns,
那么就会得到含有 n 个未知数的 n 元方程组
and solving a system of n equations with
对含有 n 个未知数的 n 元方程组
n unknowns is very expensive because if n is big,
求解非常费力 因为如果 n 很大
then at some point of our solution,
那么在某个点上的解
we have to invert an n by n matrix.
我们需要转置一个 n*n 的矩阵
Inverting a huge matrix is something that takes
转置大矩阵会耗费
a lot of time and a lot of computing power.
大量时间和计算能力
So this is simply not feasible.
所以这并不可行
So instead this is why we use gradient descent.
因此这就是我们使用梯度下降法的原因
It will not give us the exact answer necessarily but it will get us pretty
这种方法不能给出准确答案 但是可以让我们无限接近
close to the best answer which will give us a solution that fits our data pretty well.
最佳答案 给我们较好拟合数据的解答
But if we had infinite computing power,
但是如果我们具有无限的计算能力
we would just solve this system and solve linear regression in one step.
们可以解决方程组 用一个步骤解决线性回归